Prince William Symphony Orchestra records, 1974-2009
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Prince William Symphony Orchestra records
1974-2009
C0252
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
10.5 linear feet (19 boxes)
The Prince William Symphony Orchestra collection contains correspondence, press releases, organization records, programs, scrapbook pages, newspaper clippings, photographs, awards, certificates, and plaques.
Prince William Symphony Orchestra.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Sarah Nucci on November 10, 2014.
Historical Information
The Prince William Symphony Orchestra was founded in 1972. Each year, through fundraisers, donations, and tickets sales, the Prince William Symphony Orchestra performed numerous concerts and shows. The organization sent out fliers that listed the Symphony Orchestra's Spring and Fall concert schedule and encouraged people in the community to attend the performances and support the Symphony Orchestra. Although it began as a civic ensemble, it was a fully-paid ensemble by the mid-1990s. In 2010, the Prince William Symphony Orchestra began its residency in George Mason University's Hylton Performing Arts Center on the Manassas Campus. The orchestra is no longer performing.
Scope and Content
The Prince William Symphony Orchestra collection contains correspondence, press releases, organization records, programs, scrapbook pages, newspaper clippings, photographs, awards, certificates, and plaques. The bulk of these records either pertain to the Prince William Symphony Orchestra or were produced by the Prince William Symphony Orchestra. The contents of this collection span from 1974-2009.
Series 1 is titled Correspondence, press releases, and organization records. These records span from 1981-2009 and include emails between member, donors, and supporters. Additionally, this series includes advertisements, meeting minutes, documents, and the organization's Article of Incorporation.
Series 2 is titled Programs. This series includes a collection of programs from concerts and performances by the Prince William Symphony Orchestra. The earliest programs detail the 1974-1975 Fall concerts. Each folder contains additional fliers and advertisements for each performance during the spring and fall performance cycles.
Series 3 is titled Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings. The documents in this series are ordered chronologically and were created by the collection's donor. The series contains several photographs that were captured and ordered by members of the Prince William Symphony Orchestra. A variety of newspaper clippings that mention either the organization's members or operations are also included in this series.The series spans from 1979-2008.
Series 4 is titled Photographs. These photographs cover a range of organization fundraisers, sponsored events, silent auctions, and decorators' shows. In addition to these photographs, there are also many that pertain to performances, concerts, and practices. Lastly, the series contains musician and member headshots. The bulk of these photographs span the 1980s and 1990s.
Series 5 is titled Awards, certificates, and plaques. This series contains some of the awards and certificates that recognized the Prince William Symphony's excellent membership and community involvement. There are also framed office signs, adopt-a-musician advertisements, ribbons, and nametags included in this series.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into 5 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1981-2009 (Boxes 1-6)
Series 2: Programs, 1974-2009 (Boxes 7-10)
Series 3: Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1979-2008 (Boxes 11-16)
Series 4: Photographs, 1980s-1990s (Boxes 17-18)
Series 5: Awards, certificates, and plaques, 2000-2004 (Box 19)
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds many other collections on music, theater, and the performing arts.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Prince William Symphony Orchestra.
Subjects:
Symphony orchestras--United States--Virginia--Prince William County.
Document Types:
Photographic prints.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1981-2009; (6 boxes)
  The information in this series pertains to the Correspondence, press releases, and organization records produced by the Prince William Symphony Orchestra.
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1987-June 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, July 1987-December 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1988-June 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, July 1988-December 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1989-June 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, July 1989-December 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1990-June 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, July 1990-December 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1991-June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, July 1991-December 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1992-April 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, May 1992-August 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, September 1992-December 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1993-June 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, July 1993-December 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, January 1997-July 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, August 1997-December 1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, press releases, and organization records, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - PWSO car raffle, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - PWSO mission statement and policies, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - PWSO nominating committee records, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - PWSO executive board meeting minutes, September 1987-June 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - PWSO silent auction records, April 11 1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - PWSO "A financial orientation,", 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - PWSO season information, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - PWSO checks for tickets and passes, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - PWSO board of directors book, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - PWSO annual gala and silent auction sponsorship opportunity forms, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - PWSO articles of incorporation and article of amendation, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - PWSO audio and CDs, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - PWSO bylaws, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - PWSO donation solicitation packets, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - PWSO magazines and periodicals, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - PWSO musical event's advertisements, fliers, and notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 7)
    1 of 2
  - PWSO musical event's advertisements, fliers, and notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 8)
    2 of 2
  - PWSO organization forms and applications, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - PWSO ribbons and volunteer pins, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - PWSO sample employment contract, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - PWSO volunteer guidelines, job description, recruitment forms, and job listings, July 13 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - PWSO handbook, 1989-1990 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Handbook for symphony orchestra women's associations, 1980s-1990s (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Series 2: Programs, 1974-2009; (4 boxes)
  The information in this series pertains to the programs produced by the Prince William Symphony Orchestra for their concerts and performances. The materials cover each spring and fall season from 1974 to 2009.
  - Programs, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Programs, October 1976-April 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Programs, October 1977-April 1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Programs, October 1978-December 1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Programs, November 1980-May 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Programs, October 1981-May 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Programs, October 1982-May 1983 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Programs, October 1983-May 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Programs, December 1984-April 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Programs, October 1985-March 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Programs, October 1986-April 1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Programs, October 1987-May 1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Programs, October 1988-April 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Programs, October 1989-April 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Programs, August 1990-May 1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Programs, October 1991-May 1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Programs, October 1992-May 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Programs, October 1993-June 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Programs, August 1994-June 1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Programs, October 1995-May 1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Programs, November 1996-June 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Programs, September 1997-May 1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Programs, October 1998-May 1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Programs, September 1999-April 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Programs, September 2000-May 2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Programs, November 2001-May 2002 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Programs, November 2002-June 2003 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Programs, September 2003-June 2004 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Programs, October 2004-June 2005 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Programs, October 2005-May 2006 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Programs, November 2006-May 2007 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Programs, September 2008-May 2009 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Prince William Classic, 2004-2008 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Undated Programs, 1980s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1979-2008; (6 boxes)
  The materials in this series include scrapbooks, photographs and newspaper clippings that detail numerous organization fundraisers, auctions, concerts, performances, and events. The scrapbooks begin in 1979 and end in 2008.
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1980-June 1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, July 1980-December 1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1983-July 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, August 1983-December 1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1984-June 1984 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, July 1984-December 1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1985-June 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, July 1985-December 1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1987-April 1987 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, May 1987-September 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, October 1987-December 1987 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1988-June 1988 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, July 1988-December 1988 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1990-June 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, July 1990-December 1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1991-August 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, September 1991-December 1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, January 1992-June 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, July 1992-December 1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook pages and newspaper clippings, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Series 4: Photographs, 1980-1999; (2 boxes)
  The photographs included in this series were taken at the Prince William Symphony Orchestra's concert, performances, sponsored events, and group functions. The photographs cover a period spanning the 1980s and 1990s.
  - Auctions, fundraisers, and events, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Auctions, fundraisers, and events, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Concerts and performances, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 3)
    1 of 3
  - Concerts and performances, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 4)
    2 of 3
  - Concerts and performances, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 5)
    3 of 3
  - "Concerts Under the Stars,", July 1991-August 1991 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Decorators' show, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Musician headshots, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Musician headshots, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Negatives, 1980s-1990s (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - New years gala, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Scholarship competitors, 1980s-1990s (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - String quartets and trios, 1980s-1990s (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Unidentifiable subject matter, 1980s-1990s (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Series 5: Awards, certificates, and plaques, 2000-2004; (1 box)
  This series includes awards and certificates from 2000-2004 that acknowledge and celebrate the Prince William Symphony Orchestra's excellent membership and role in the surrounding communities.
  - PWSO adopt-a-musician plaques, 1980s-1990s (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - PWSO certificate of recognition, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - PWSO framed office sign, 1980s-1990s (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - PWSO member of the year award, 2003-2004 (Box 19, Folder 4)